ovationtix.com 2019-08-06

# Privacy Policy | AudienceView | Ticket Selling Software

**AudienceView Ticketing Corporation**

**Privacy & Cookies Policy**

Updated and Effective as of May 22, 2019

This website (and any mobile site or mobile application that links to this Privacy Policy) (collectively, the “ **Sites** ”) is owned and operated by AudienceView Ticketing Corporation (an Ontario corporation with its principal place of business at 200 Wellington Street West, 2nd Floor, Toronto, Ontario, Canada M5V 3C7) (“ **AudienceView** “, “ **we** ”, “ **our** ”, and “ **us** ”). 

At AudienceView, we are committed to respecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy explains how we collect, use and disclose personal information that we receive when you visit the Sites, or communicate with us both on the Sites and offline as a business customer, prospective customer or general contact.   AudienceView has developed policies and procedures consistent with the _Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act_ (“ **PIPEDA** ”), the EU General Data Protection Regulation ( **GDPR** ) and other relevant privacy laws.  

This Privacy Policy applies to AudienceView and its subsidiaries, including AudienceView Ticketing (UK) Limited, an AudienceView affiliate’s product website (www.ovationtix.com), and, for GDPR purposes, covers our processing activities as a data controller. We also process personal information as a data processor on behalf of our customers (please see “ _AudienceView as Data Processor_ ” below).  

The Sites are not intended for or directed at children under the age of 16 years and we do not knowingly collect information relating to children under this age. 

We are not required to appoint a formal data protection officer under data protection laws. However, we have designated a Privacy/Data Protection Compliance team who you can reach out to about any queries you may have in relation to this Privacy Policy. If you are located in the EEA, you can contact our representative(s) in the EEA about any data protection queries, using the contact details below. 

AudienceView Ticketing Corporation’s representative in the UK is AudienceView Ticketing (UK) Limited.

**Contacting Us**

If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy or your information, or to exercise any of your rights as described in this Privacy Policy or under data protection laws, you can contact us as follows:

Outside of the EEA

By mail:  
Privacy/Data Protection Compliance AudienceView Ticketing Corporation, 200 Wellington Street West, 2nd Floor, Toronto, Ontario, Canada M5V 3C7

By telephone:

(416) 687-2000

By email:

gdpr+privacy@audienceview.com

In the EEA

By post:

AudienceView Ticketing (UK) Limited, 9 Great Russell Street, London WC1B 3NH, United Kingdom

By telephone:

+44 20 3005 4580

By email:

gdpr+privacy@audienceview.com

**Topics**

Data Protection/Privacy Principles

Personal Information We Collect

AudienceView as Data Processor

What We Do With Your Personal InformationDisclosure of Your Personal Information to Third Parties

International Transfers

Security of Your Personal Information

How Long We Keep Your Personal Information

Right to Object

Exercising Your Rights

Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies

Links

Complaints

Changes to Our Privacy Policy

**Data Protection/Privacy Principles**

AudienceView adheres to the following fair information principles when processing your personal information as data controller:

  * **Accountability – AudienceView is responsible for personal information and data under its control and will designate an individual accountable for our compliance with this Privacy Policy.**

  * Lawfulness, fairness and transparency – personal information and data must be processed lawfully, fairly and in a transparent manner. 

  * Purpose identification and limitation – personal information and data must be collected for specified, explicit and legitimate purposes and not further processed in a manner that is incompatible with those purposes.  AudienceView will identify the purposes for which personal information is collected at or before the time the information is collected.

  * Data minimisation – personal information and data must be adequate, relevant and limited to what is necessary in relation to the purposes for which they are processed. 

  * Accuracy – personal information and data must be accurate and, where necessary, kept up to date. 

  * Storage limitation – personal information and data must be kept in a form which permits identification of data subjects for no longer than is necessary for the purposes for which the personal information are processed.

  * Integrity and confidentiality – personal information and data must be processed in a manner that ensures appropriate security of the personal information, including protection against unauthorised or unlawful processing and against accidental loss, destruction or damage by using appropriate technical or organisational measures. 

* * *

**PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

_Information you give us_

You may provide us with information through the Sites, by email, over the phone or otherwise communicate or are in contact with us as a business customer or business contact, when you:

  * request additional information about our services or ask us to contact you;
  * use our services as a client or customer;
  * receive client support from AudienceView;
  * register with us on the Sites; and
  * make any comment or contribution on our Sites.

The categories of personal information you provide may include:

  * first and last name;
  * job title and company name;
  * email address;
  * phone number
  * mailing address;
  * password to register with us;
  * your personal or professional interests;
  * the category or type of organization you work for;
  * information that you may submit to us via posting on our forums;
  * any other identifier that permits AudienceView to make contact with you.

We do not generally seek to collect sensitive personal information (also known as “special categories of personal data”) through our Sites. Sensitive personal information is information relating to racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade-union membership; health or sex life, sexual orientation; genetic or biometric information. If we do collect sensitive personal information, we will ask for your explicit consent to our proposed use of that information at the time of collection.

_Information we collect from you_

AudienceView collects, stores and uses information about your visits to the Sites and about your computer, tablet, mobile or other device (“device”) through which you access the Sites. This includes the following information:

  * technical information, including the Internet protocol (IP) address, browser type, internet service provider, device identifier, your login information, time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform, and geographical location;
  * information about your visits and use of the Site, including the full Uniform Resource Locators (URL), clickstream to, through and from our Site, pages you viewed and searched for, page response times, length of visits to certain pages, referral source/exit pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks and mouse-overs), and website navigation and search terms used.

**AUDIENCEVIEW AS DATA PROCESSOR**

We collect and process personal information on behalf of our clients in the provision of our services. In these circumstances, AudienceView is acting as a data processor and our clients remain the data controller in respect of personal information they provide to us. To the extent that we are acting as data processor, we will process such personal information in accordance with our customer’s instructions and any agreement in place with our customers. AudienceView will only use such personal information for the purposes of providing the services for which our clients have engaged us.

Our clients are responsible for ensuring that the privacy of individuals whose personal information they are processing is respected, including communicating to these individuals in their own privacy policies with whom the individual’s personal information is being shared and by whom it is being processed.

As a data processor, AudienceView may share personal information where instructed by our clients (the data controller). With our client’s specific or general authorisation, we may also share personal information with third party service providers (sub-processors) who work for AudienceView and who are subject to security and confidentiality obligations.   

Details of all sub-processors engaged by AudienceView from time to time can be viewed here: [www.AudienceView.com/subprocessors](http://audienceview.com/subprocessors/)

Moreover, AudienceView may provide personal information to comply with a subpoena, warrant or other court order, government institution requesting the information upon lawful authority, or as may be otherwise required by law. 

Where AudienceView is acting as a data processor, we will refer any request from an individual for access to personal information which we hold about them to our clients. AudienceView will not respond directly to the request.

AudienceView will retain personal information which we process on behalf of our  clients for as long as needed to provide services to our customers and in accordance with any agreement in place with our  clients.

Personal information does not include information that is aggregated or anonymized in such a manner that it cannot be connected to any individual. We may anonymise and aggregate the personal information we process in such a way as to ensure that individuals cannot be identified from it. We may use this anonymised and aggregated information for our own purposes including for testing our systems, research, data analysis, developing new services and improving the Sites and our services. We may share this anonymized and aggregated information with third parties.

* * *

**WHAT WE DO WITH YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

As a data controller, AudienceView will only use your personal information if we have a legal basis for doing so. The purpose for which we use and process your information and the legal basis on which we carry out each type of processing is explained in the table below.

**Purposes for which we will process the information** | **Legal Basis for the processing**  
---|---  
To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into with our clients and to provide services to our clients. | It is in our legitimate interests to process your personal information in order to enter into a contract with our clients and to fulfil our contractual obligations to our clients.  
To provide you with information and materials that you request from us. | It is in our legitimate interests to respond to your queries and provide any information and materials requested in order to generate and develop business. To ensure we offer an efficient service, we consider this use to be proportionate and will not be prejudicial or detrimental to you.  
To personalise our services and the Sites to you. | It is in our legitimate interests to enhance your experience on our Sites and to better our services. We consider this use to be proportionate and will not be prejudicial or detrimental to you.  
If you do not wish to receive tailored or personalised information from us based on personal information you have provided us, please contact us as set out in “Contacting Us” above.  
To enforce our client agreements. | It is in our legitimate interests to enforce our client agreements. We consider this use to be necessary for our legitimate interests and proportionate.  
To update you on services and benefits we offer, either directly or through third party partners. | It is in our legitimate interests to market our services and related services. We consider this use to be proportionate and will not be prejudicial or detrimental to you.

If you would prefer not to receive any direct marketing communications from us, you can opt-out at any time by contacting us as set out in “Contacting Us” above.

For direct marketing sent by email to new contacts (i.e. individuals who we have not previously engaged with), we need your consent to send you unsolicited direct marketing.  
  
To send you information regarding changes to our policies, other terms and conditions and other administrative information. | It is in our legitimate interests to ensure that any changes to our policies and other terms are communicated to you. We consider this use to be necessary for our legitimate interests and will not be prejudicial or detrimental to you.  
  
  * To administer our Sites including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes;
  * To improve our Sites to ensure that consent is presented in the most effective manner for you and your device; and
  * To keep our Sites safe and secure.

| For all these categories, it is in our legitimate interests to continually monitor and improve our services and your experience of the Sites and to ensure network security. We consider this use to be necessary for our legitimate interests and will not be prejudicial or detrimental to you.  
To measure or understand the effectiveness of any marketing we provide to you and others, and to deliver relevant marketing to you. | It is in our legitimate interests to continually improve our offering and to develop our business. We consider this use to be necessary in order to effectively generate business and will not be prejudicial or detrimental to you.  
  
Where you provide consent, you can withdraw your consent at any time and free of charge, but without affecting the lawfulness of processing based on consent before its withdrawal. You can update your details or change your privacy preferences by contacting us as set out in “Contacting Us” above.

AudienceView will only use your personal information for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If we need to use your personal information for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you in a timely manner and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so or seek your consent for using your personal information for the new purpose.

* * *

**DISCLOSURE OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA TO THIRD PARTIES**

AudienceView will not sell, rent, lease or otherwise share your personal information other than as outlined in this Privacy Policy or without obtaining your consent beforehand.

We may share your personal information with our group companies and affiliates as necessary to carry out the purposes for which the information was supplied or collected (i.e. to provide the services you have requested).  

Personal information may also be shared with our third party service providers and business partners who assist with the running of the Sites and in providing and developing our services including hosting providers, email service providers, marketing service providers, marketing partners, support community and documentation provider, and application extensions. Such third party service providers and business partners will only use your personal information for the purposes identified in this Privacy Policy and are subject to security and confidentiality obligations and are only permitted to process your personal information for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.

In addition, AudienceView may disclose information about you:

  * in the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal information to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets;
  * if all or substantially all of AudienceView’s assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal information held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets; 
  * if we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal information in order to comply with any legal or regulatory obligation;
  * if necessary to protect the vital interests of a person; and
  * to enforce or apply our terms and conditions or to establish, exercise or defend the rights of AudienceView, our staff, customers or others.

* * *

**INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS**

To deliver services to you, it is necessary for us to transfer your personal information outside of the European Economic Area (“ **EEA** ”) to our affiliates/group companies and our service providers and business partners located outside the EEA. This includes the USA and Canada. 

The European Commission has decided that Canada provides adequate levels of data protection.

Where personal information is transferred to and stored in a country not determined by the European Commission as providing adequate levels of protection for personal information, we take steps to provide appropriate safeguards to protect your personal information, including:

  * entering into standard contractual clauses approved by the European Commission, obliging recipients to protect your personal information;
  * under the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework which enables U.S. business to self-certify as a means of complying with EU data protection laws (see below). 

If you want further information on the specific mechanism used by us when transferring your personal information out of the EEA, please contact us using the details set out above.

* * *

**SECURITY OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

AudienceView uses appropriate technical and organizational security measures to protect personal information both online and offline from unauthorized use, loss, alteration or destruction. We use industry standard physical and procedural security measures to protect information from the point of collection to the point of destruction. This includes but is not limited to: encryption, firewalls, access controls, policies and other procedures to protect information from unauthorized access.

Only authorized personnel and third party service providers are permitted access to personal information, and that access is limited by need. Where data processing is carried out on our behalf by a third party, we take steps to ensure that appropriate security measures are in place to prevent unauthorized disclosure of personal information.

Despite these precautions, however, AudienceView cannot guarantee the security of information transmitted over the Internet or that unauthorized persons will not obtain access to personal information. In the event of a data breach, AudienceView have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where required to do so by law.

If you have any questions about security on our Sites, you can contact us as set out in “Contacting Us” above.

* * *

**HOW LONG WE KEEP YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

Your personal information will not be kept for longer than is necessary for the purposes for which it was collected and processed. We will retain your personal information for as long as your account is active, as defined below, or as needed to provide you with services you have requested. 

The criteria we use for retaining different types of personal information, includes the following: 

  * **General queries** – when you make an enquiry via our Sites or contact us by email or telephone, we will retain your information for as long as necessary to respond to your queries. After this period, we will not hold your personal information for longer than one year if we have not had any active subsequent contact with you;
  * **Direct marketing** – where we hold your personal information on our database for direct marketing purposes, we will retain your information for no longer than two years if we have not had any active subsequent contact with you. 
  * **Legal and regulatory requirements** – we may need to retain personal information for up 7 years after we cease providing services to you where necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes or enforce our terms and conditions.

* * *

**YOUR RIGHTS**

**ACCESS TO AND UPDATING YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

You have the right to access information which we hold about you (“ **data subject access request** ”). 

You may also have the right to receive personal information which you have provided to us in a structured and commonly used format so that it can be transferred to another data controller (“ **data portability** ”). The right to data portability only applies where your personal data is processed by us with your consent or for the performance of a contract and when processing is carried out by automated means.

We want to make sure that your personal information is accurate and up to date. You may ask us to correct or remove information you think is inaccurate. Please keep us informed if your personal information changes during your relationship with us.

* * *

**RIGHT TO OBJECT**

_Direct marketing_

You have the right to object at any time to our processing of your personal information for direct marketing purposes.

_Where we process your information based on our legitimate interests_

You also have the right to object, on grounds relating to your particular situation, at any time to processing of your personal information which is based on our legitimate interests. Where you object on this ground, we shall no longer process your personal information unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests, rights and freedoms or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

* * *

**YOUR OTHER RIGHTS**

You also have the following rights under data protection laws to request that we rectify your personal information which is inaccurate or incomplete.

In certain circumstances, you have the right to: 

  * request the erasure of your personal information erasure (“ **right to be forgotten** ”);
  * restrict the processing of your personal information to processing in certain circumstances.

Please note that the above rights are not absolute and we may be entitled to refuse requests, wholly or partly, where exceptions under the applicable law apply. 

For example, we may refuse a request for erasure of personal information where the processing is necessary to comply with a legal obligation or necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims. We may refuse to comply with a request for restriction if the request is manifestly unfounded or excessive.

* * *

**EXERCISING YOUR RIGHTS**

You can exercise any of your rights as described in this Privacy Policy and under data protection laws by contacting us as set out in “Contacting Us” above.

Save as described in this Privacy Policy or provided under data protection laws, there is no charge for the exercise of your legal rights. However, if your requests are manifestly unfounded or excessive, in particular because of their repetitive character, we may either: (a) charge a reasonable fee taking into account the administrative costs of providing the information or taking the action requested; or (b) refuse to act on the request.

Where we have reasonable doubts concerning the identity of the person making the request, we may request additional information necessary to confirm your identity.

* * *

**COOKIES**

In order to improve the Sites, we use small files commonly known as “cookies”. A cookie is a small amount of data which often includes a unique identifier that is sent to your device from the Sites and is stored on your device’s browser or hard drive. 

We use cookies to:

  * recognise whenever you visit the Sites,
  * obtain information about your preferences and use of the Sites;
  * carry out research and statistical analysis to help improve our content and services and to help us better understand our users’ requirements; and
  * target our marketing and advertising campaigns more effectively by providing interest-based  advertisements that are personalized to your interests; and
  * make your online experience more efficient and enjoyable.

For further information on our use of cookies, please see below.

We currently use the following third party cookies:

Third Party Cookies | Cookie Name(s) | Purpose | Link   
---|---|---|---  
Google Analytics | _ga, _gid | These cookies provide us with a visitor count and an understanding of how visitors move around and use the Sites. We can then use this information to improve navigability and the Sites generally – please see further details below  | [Google Privacy Policy](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245)  
Marketo | _mkto_trk | These cookies enable us to recognise your browser and help us to track visits to the Sites and also to recognise a return visitor as a unique user. For example, if you provide us with your name and email address on the Sites, we will know your identity when you visit the Sites at a later date. | [Marketo Privacy Policy](https://www.marketo.com/company/legal/)  
SalesForce | BrowserId, _gat, force-proxy-stream, force-stream, renderCTX, sfdc-stream, | These cookies enable the AvConnect support portal, improving the site experience, provide enhanced, more personal features, recall changes made to text size, fonts and other parts of the web pages that you can customize. | [Salesforce Privacy Policy](https://www.salesforce.com/ca/company/privacy/)  
Adroll | __adroll | These cookies enable us to recognise your browser and help us to track visitors for targeted advertising purposes. The cookie enables AdRoll to target advertising on other sites or applications based on your online activity. | [Adroll Privacy Policy](https://www.adrollgroup.com/privacy)  
  
We ask for your consent to place cookies on your device, except where these are essential for us to provide you with a service that you have requested.

If you don’t want us to use cookies when you use the Sites, you can set your internet browser to not accept cookies. However, if you block cookies some of the features on the Sites may not function as a result.

You can opt-out of receiving targeted advertisements by visiting the NAI website opt-out page here: [http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1) or the DAA opt-out page here: [https://www.aboutads.info/](http://www.aboutads.info/) or, for end users located in European Territories, the EDAA opt-out page here: [http://youronlinechoices.eu/](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)

You can find more information about how to manage cookies for all the commonly used internet browsers by visiting [www.aboutallcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). This website will also explain how you can delete cookies which are already stored on your device.

* * *

**LINKS **

The Sites may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our business partners, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and AudienceView does not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal information to these websites.

* * *

**COMPLAINTS**

If you have any questions or complaints regarding our Privacy Policy or practices, please contact us as set out in “Contacting Us” above.

If you are in located in the EEA, you also have the right to complain to the relevant supervisory authority in the EEA. In the UK, this is the Information Commissioner’s Office ([https://ico.org.uk/](https://ico.org.uk/))

* * *

**CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY**

AudienceView reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy from time to time. Any changes will be posted on this page with an updated revision date. If we make any material changes to this Privacy Policy, we will notify you by email or by means of a prominent notice on the Sites prior to the change becoming effective.
